Asuna!
Alice's Light Cube has been ejected!
Grab Kirigaya and log out!
Hurry up!
I'm sorry Rank but I
I decided I'm going to
stay but you you don't
have to you'll like Alice.
She's really sweet please take care
of her she has the biggest heart and
everyone who knows her Loves her so
many sacrifice themselves for her so
please don't let them turn her into
a weapon For their sake and Kirito's
also please tell our friends I said
thank you and I'm sorry and goodbye.
I don't know how much
you can go to the end.
Now I'm going to take a step and run away.
You can't be strong enough.
Let's see, I'll go back.
I'm not sure what I am.
But I don't know how much you feel like.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
Thank you.
...and I will keep it in mind...
...and I will
keep it
in
mind...
I have Alice's light
cube with me. She's safe.
But, um, Asuna decided to
stay in there with Kirigaya.
She did, huh?
All right, we'll hurry it up then.
Get ready to pop the locks on
the bulkhead when I call back.
Dr.
Kojuro
Agents are standing by the bulkhead.
It's clear so far.
Just give the word!
Thanks, will do.
One minute since the
acceleration phase started.
Ten years have already passed in there.
Come on, Higa!
Kikuoka, hurry.
I bet you're thinking this is out
of character for me, aren't you?
No.
Well, sort of.
I figured as much.
I have a good reason for
doing this, you know?
Oh, you do?
Yes.
I always consider the worst-case scenario.
For now, I want to let the hijackers think
they still have a chance to get Alice.
Let's hope they don't notice us.
Rank, we're at the hatch now.
Go ahead and disable the lock.
What the?
They opened the goddamn bulkhead again.
But they got Alice already.
They should be kicking back and
waiting for the JSDF to roll in.
Unless...
Hmm... That's it.
Rig, you're with me.
Everyone else, lock and load
and head for the stairs.
Waste anything that comes
down and secure that bulkhead.
He makes it sound like a cakewalk.
You got something for me to do or what?
You're coming along with me
to check out this cable duct.
I have a feeling our friends at Wrath
are looking for something in there.
All right, let's go say hi.
Dad, looks like he fell.
He's the mole Captain Miller hired.
Guess they found out and
chucked him down the shaft.
Shit!
Holy crap!
Are you okay? Keeks!
Damn, that stings.
Don't worry. I'm good.
Just took a round of the vest.
How about you? You're okay?
Yeah, I am.
Me and the old laptop gotta scare us all.
Good.
Keep on working, then.
They're not screwing around.
Guess it's time to scuttle
this rig and get the hell off.
Not my call though.
Better get the captain and let him know!
Who's that?
No!
Oh my god!
That's me!
What is this?
You finally crossed
over, Gabe. That's all.
Alicia?
Have you been waiting
here all this time, alone?
You're so cold.
Come on, let go of my hand.
I won't, Gabe.
You and I will be together from now on.
Come, let's go.
No! Stop!
Let me go!
No!
Stop it!
Let go of me!
No!
Ah!
Yo, Cap!
Wrath is zealous and they...
C...
Cap...ton?
Get your ass up the captains.
Those bastards killed brig yeah
captain to saga or dead, too?
Don't bother.
There's no reason to
risk our lives anymore.
They got Ellis' light cube.
So, we still have our orders, don't we?
If we can't get it, we destroy it.
You know how to set that up, huh?
Yeah, I got an idea.
But without the cap, it's a call
that's way over my pay grade.
Tell me.
Tell me!
The...
the engine.
Over ten minutes have gone by so far.
And Kirigaya and Asuna's Fluctlights will
reach the limit of their
memory capacity soon.
Doctor.
Looks like the hijackers are retreating.
They... they are?
They're heading down to the
Ocean Turtle submarine dock.
And they're in a hurry.
What's that?
Did something hit us? Checking.
Oh no.
Dr.
Kojiro, that jolt was caused by
our engine firing up to full power!
Meaning?
We may have a problem.
The main engine at the bottom of the
shaft is a pressurized water reactor.
Those bastards!
Look at that.
They planted C4 on that tank.
The CRD's under it.
And if that's destroyed,
the control rods can't drop.
The core will melt down what do we do?
I'll go down there and disarm the bomb
I'm sure the hijackers gave themselves
enough time to get far enough away
before it blows that gives me about
I don't know five to ten minutes but
the temperature down there by now it's
got to be boiling true but it's It's
not hotter than your typical sauna.
I'll rush in, yink the detonator,
and be out in a few seconds.
But...
Nakanishi!
Keeks, he's screwed with the reactor.
Sounded like it.
Don't worry about that.
Just keep working.
Shut those STLs down.
Okay.
Say, Higa.
You don't need me right now, do you? No.
Wait!
You're not going down there!
Don't worry.
I just want to scope out
the situation, is all.
It shouldn't take long.
A few minutes, Tops.
Well, see you in a bit. Good luck.
Watch your back down there.
Oh, crap. Geeks.
They either left him behind to die.
Or he's nuts.
What the?
It's Niemon.
But what's piloting it?
Hi, Rank!
Akihiko!
It's you!
I'm sorry I left you on your own.
The way I did.
You've been here?
All this time?
Rank, I was blessed to
have you in my life.
I was so lost in my work,
and you were the only thing keeping
me connected to the real world.
And now, I'd like you to
maintain that connection.
Bridge the gap between the
real and virtual worlds.
Fulfill my dream.
Yes, I will.
I will.
It's getting shot to pieces.
I better move.
Are you hit?
Akihiko.
Oh no, the battery cable's damaged.
It's only a matter of time
before it stops functioning.
I'll make it.
You can do it.
Please, Akihiko!
He had lost power.
That's it.
Come on, Akihiko!
Your Heathcliff of the
Divine Blade, remember?
The greatest rival kiddy-toe the Black
Sourceman ever had, and he never gave up!
If that kid could do the
impossible, then so can you!
I can't believe it. It's moving.
You did it.
Looks like they disarmed the bomb.
I can't believe Hans decided to stay.
Well, him and Brig were
always tight, so...
That's that, I guess.
Only two?
Damn it, Shaq! What?
Didn't I tell you guys to
grab and bag all the bodies?
There's only two of them here. Well, yeah.
There was only Brig and Captain Miller.
We did a sweep and they were it.
But wasn't there one more in the STL room?
No, man. Just the cap. That's it.
His face freaked the hell out of me.
Rank, log out for Kirito
and Asuna is almost done.
One minute to go.
All right.
Hang in there.
I'll send someone down to get you.
Thanks.
In the shape I'm in, I doubt I'd
make it one rung up this ladder.
Heeks went down to check on whatever
was going on with the engine.
He was bleeding pretty bad when he left.
Do you know if he's okay?
Oh, he's better than okay.
He ran in there guns a-blazing.
Just like the hero in an action movie.
I wish I saw that.
Oh, sweet.
Thirty seconds left to log out.
Okay, I'll head over to Kirigaya's room.
I've got my comms on if you need anything.
Over.
Dr. Kochiro, come in.
We're uh in the engine room yes i'm
here is something wrong well we removed
the explosive from the tank but um
Niemon he's um gone
what where'd he go
come on guys come back to us
please be okay please Please.
Thank you so much for watching.
I didn't go.
Asuna...
I knew if I left you alone,
you'd turn into a crybaby.
I know you pretty well,
if I do say so myself.
When we get back home, I bet
Alice will be so angry with us.
Maybe not, as long as
we still remember her.
And the time we spent with her.
If we don't forget that, we're good.
Yeah.
We won't forget Alice.
Or Liz.
Or Klein.
Or Aikiel and Silica.
Or our little Yui.
As long as we remember
them, we'll be alright.
Won't we?
So how long will we be living here again?
About 200 years give or take.
I could do a thousand years!
Easy if I'm with you.
All righty then, let's go.
Yeah, let's get going.
It's a new world now,
and we've got lots to do.
Let's see if we can help it out.
Thank you.